From the Ruins came Hope and Despair
The Big Lift is a war, drama, romance film directed by George Seaton.
The Berlin Air Lift from the point of view of two Air Force NCOs who
navigate romance in a bombed out post WW2 Germany.
Sgt. 1st Class Danny MacCullough, played by Montgomery Clift.
MSgt. Henry "Hank" Kowalski, played by Paul Douglas.
Frederica Burkhardt, played by Cornell Borchers.
Gerda, played by Bruni Löbel.
Stieber, played by O.E. Hasse.
Capt. Dante V. Morel, played by Dante V. Morel.
The Big Lift is a 1950 American drama war film on location in the city of Berlin, Germany, that tells the
story of "Operation Vittles", the 1948–49 Berlin Airlift, through the experiences of two U.S.
Air Force sergeants played by Montgomery Clift and Paul Douglas.
The film was directed and written by George Seaton, and was released April 26, 1950, less than one
year after the Soviet blockade of Berlin was lifted and airlift operations ceased.
Because the film was shot in Berlin in 1949, as well as using newsreel footage of the actual airlift, it provides a contemporary
glimpse of the post-war state of the city as its people struggled to recover from the devastation wrought by World War II.
The film explores themes of berlin, germany, u.s. air force,
woman between two men, airlift, post war germany.
The tone is emotional.